CALEB OTIENO

| +2547 14 531 574 | | +2547 41 795 362 | olelecaleb176@gmail.com

Websites, Portfolio, Profiles

- https://www.behance.net/drotienoo
- http://caleboleshii.blogspot.com/

Professional Summary

Creative UI&UX Designer with over 5 years facilitating and supporting human interactions with complex systems and software. Maintains user-centric designs while adhering to prescribed interface principals and related development goals. Dedicated to creating inviting and unintimidating interfaces for everything from simple open-source applications to complex exclusive systems.

Creative Copy Writer offering background in preparing well-structured drafts, editing posts and conducting keyword research. Collaborative team player possessing impeccable grammar and in-depth comprehension of Microsoft Word and Office.

Skills

- Graphic design
- ❖ User Interface (UI) and User Experience (UX) design
- Complex Problem Solving
- Draft Development
- ❖ CSS & HTML
- Microsoft Office
- Adobe Systems Software
- Digital Marketing

Work History

Senior UI/UX Designer, Nayvy. Inc

Nairobi, KE | Dec 2021 to September, 2022

- Monitored emerging UX design trends and practices for useful techniques and cutting-edge
- developments suitable for integration into future projects.
- Participated in Navvy design review meetings to brainstorm new UX developments through
- collaborative thinking.
- Analyzed user feedback to influence future UX updates, enhancing user concerns and pain points

- during subsequent patch cycles.
- Maximized system performance, enhancing end-user experience by applying iterative back end
- development updates.
- Collaborated with teammates to deliver valuable features meeting business and customer needs

Sales Promoter, KOKO NETWORKS | Kenya

December 2022.

- Listened to what customers want and helping them find the perfect product for their needs.
- Constantly building product knowledge and delivering this knowledge in engaging ways.
- Delivered presentations and demonstrations to customers and other stakeholders.
- Engaged in meaningful interactions and building good relationships with customers.
- Distributed samples and providing feedback for improvement to the management team.
- Following up with customers and providing guidance on product selection.
- Meeting daily targets and submitting sales reports.
- Networking with relevant stakeholders.
- Searching for new business opportunities.

Polling Clerk, IEBC

August 2022

- Verified the voter's name and ID (and voter's card number) in the voters' register
- Identified a voter electronically.
- Ensured the security of election materials under their custody
- Managed queues and directed voters to respective polling stations.
- Ensured that voters vote in secret and place their ballot papers in the (correct) ballot box.
- Worked in stringent proximity with the Presiding Officer, also offering any necessary aid.

Senior Graphic Designer, and Marketer

Jeysell Co. Ltd | Nairobi | July 2022

- Brainstormed on new ideas on the company's brands through market research.
- Solved major customer needs through designs.
- Designed posters, and other company's designs for social media consumption.
- A member of the digital marketing executive board.
- Lead generation as per the company's statutory on a daily basis.

Article And Content Writer, College Aftermath (Indian Company)

Remote, Jan 2022- February 2022

- Wrote and edited high-quality content and visually impactful programs under deadline pressure with exciting, captivating and authentic approach.
- Utilized exceptional writing, editing and proofreading skills to produce engaging and errorfree content.
- Completed thorough research into assigned topics.
- Organized material to research and complete writing tasks.

Graphic Designer, and UI/UX Design; Merit Graphic Designs Ltd

Nairobi, KE | Dec 2016 to Feb 2022

- Designed website and apps layouts, templates and unique branded looks.
- Developed creative design for print materials, brochures, banners and signs.
- Created digital image files for use in digital and traditional printing methods.
- Met with customers to present mockups and collect information for adjustments.
- Applied knowledge of production to create high-quality images.
- Put together videos for social media, advertising and informational purposes.

Cyber Technician, Winscom Cyber

Nairobi | KE | Nov 2018 - March 2021

- Computer troubleshooting and fixing technical issues.
- Quickly learned new skills and applied them to daily tasks, improving efficiency and productivity.
- Carried out day-day duties accurately and efficiently.
- Demonstrated respect, friendliness and willingness to help wherever needed.
- Worked flexible hours and shifts.
- Maintained energy and enthusiasm in fast-paced environment.
- Served customers and followed outlined steps of service.

Computer Trainer, Colmac Computer College

Busia | KE | March 2016 - Sep 2016

- Trained and developed students' skills in word-processing, spreadsheet and database programs.
- Tested and evaluated student progress to determine effectiveness and impact of teaching
- methods, materials and projects.
- Taught correct hand placement for typing and basic computer skills.
- Used lectures, demonstrations and discussions to instruct students individually and in small
- groups.

• Planned and implemented curriculum to teach up-to-date technology to the students.

Education

- 2016 2022 Kenyatta University Bachelor of Arts (BA).
- 2012 -2015 St. Mary Burumba Secondary School KCSE B (Plain)
- 2002- 2011 St. Mary's Burumba Primary School KCPE.

Other Attained Quanlifications

- Certificate in computer application, FERORA COMPUTER COLLEGE, Busia.
- Certificate of participation in Google Digital and Marketing Training at Kenyatta University.
- Certificate of Merit in STEP training (An entrepreneurial Training) at Kenyatta University.
- Certificate of completion in HTML & CSS course at Solo Learn.
- Certificate of Leadership and Mentorship, Kenyatta University.